Guide to the Ithaca Airways records, 1927-1942
Ithaca Airways records, 1972-1942
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ithaca Airways records, 1927-1942.
3169
Ithaca Airways.
1.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, cancelled checks, deposit slips, notes, mortgages, cancelled stock certificates, invoices, ledger books, cashbooks, checkbooks, receipt books, bank books, a daybook, training forms, maps, notes, exams, pamphlets, an atlas, logbooks, personal papers, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of Ithaca Airways, which was founded by Herbert M. Peters in Ithaca, Tompkins County, New York. It later became Ithaca Flying Service Inc.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Ithaca Airways was founded by Herbert M. Peters in Ithaca, Tompkins County, New York. It later became Ithaca Flying Service Inc.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records include correspondence, 1928-29, and Ithaca Airways miscellany; financial records including cancelled checks, deposit slips, notes, mortgages, cancelled stock certificates, and invoices, 1928-40, also ledger books, cashbooks, checkbooks, receipt books, and bank books for the Ithaca Airways Corporation and the Ithaca Flying Service, 1928-42, also one daybook of the Cornell Flying Club, 1935-36; pilot information including training forms, maps, notes, exams, pamphlets, an atlas, and logbooks, 1929-41; and Herbert M. Peters' personal papers including financial records and miscellany, 1927-42; and Dorothy B. Peters' records as treasurer for Girl Scout Camp Comstock 1939, and School District 16, Town of Ulysses, 1939.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ithaca Airways.; Peters, Dorothy B.; Peters, Herbert M., d.1972.; Cornell Flying Club.; Girl Scout Camp Comstock.; Ithaca Flying Service, Inc.
Subjects:
Aeronautics.; Airlines.; Airplanes--Piloting.; Air pilots.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--Commerce.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ithaca Airways Miscellany, ca. 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Financial Records
  - Ithaca Airways, cancelled checks, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ithaca Airways, cancelled checks, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ithaca Airways, cancelled checks, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ithaca Airways, deposit slips, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Ithaca Flying Service, cancelled checks, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Ithaca Airways, notes, mortgages, and cancelled stock certificates, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - NY Telephone, NYSEG and Mohawk Gas, invoices, 1930, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Ithaca Airways, Gas Statiion Statements, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ithaca Airways, Adding Machine Division - Morse Products, invoices, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ithaca Flying Service, Air Associates Inc. invoices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cayuga Lumber Co. and Cotton and Hanlan, invoices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Continental Motors Corp., invoices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - D.B. Stewart & Co. Inc., invoices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ithaca Flying Service, invoices and War Dept. notices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Lohr & Kramer, invoices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Piper Aircraft Corp., invoices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ithaca Flying Service, Texaco invoices, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Warner Aircraft Corp., invoices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Invoices, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
  - Ithaca Airways, misc. bills and receipts, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ithaca Flying Service, financial statements (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ithaca Airways, tax reports, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Ithaca Flying Service, financial book, 1929-1934 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ledger book with names and sum pd. (alphabetical), 1935-1936 (Box 2, Volume 1)
  - Daybook - property of Cornell Flying Club, with loose pages listing enrollment, 1935-1936 (Box 2, Volume 2)
  - Ledger - accounts book with names and sums pd., 1934-1935 (Box 2, Volume 3)
  - Cashbook - labelled charge - alphabetical names and sum pd., 1936-1937 (Box 2, Volume 4)
  - Cashbook - labelled Robinson, Kellogg and Storage - listing parts, labor, and sums, 1936-1938 (Box 2, Volume 5)
  - Journal - labelled Daybook with expenses and sums, 1939-1941 (Box 2, Volume 6)
  - Genesee Composition Book, Sept. 18, 1934 (Box 3, Volume 1)
  - Check book stubs - H.M. Peters, 1936-1938 (Box 3, Volume 2)
  - Check book stubs - H.M. Peters, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Volume 3)
  - Check book stubs - H.M. Peters, 1940 (Box 3, Volume 4)
  - Receipt book, 1928-1930 (Box 3, Volume 5)
  - Receipt book, 1928 (Box 3, Volume 6)
  - Bank book for Ithaca Flying Service, Tompkins Co. Trust Co., 1935-1937 (Box 3, Volume 7)
  - Check book, 1928 (Box 3, Volume 8)
  - Check book, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Volume 9)
  - Check book, 1935 (Box 3, Volume 10)
  - Check book, 1941 (Box 3, Volume 11-13)
  - Check book, 1942 (Box 3, Volume 14)
- Pilot Information
  - Department of Commerce Civil Aeronautics Admin. Civilian Pilot Training forms: 589 A-D, 527 A-D (Box 4)
  - Dept. of Commerce information including maps and notes, ca. 1935 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1 Pilot kit (Box 4)
  - Complete Exam, Questions and Answers, Civil Air Regulations for Student and Private Pilots (Box 4, Volume 1)
  - Elementary Aerodynamics, K.D. Wood (Box 4, Volume 2)
  - Notes on the Interpretation of Aeroplane Photographs (Box 4, Volume 3)
  - Notes on the Interpretation of Aeroplane Photographs, illustrations to accompany (Box 4, Volume 4)
  - U.S. Naval Air Station, Pensacola, Fla., Flight School Training (Box 4, Volume 5)
  - Dept. of Commerce, Violation Report forms (Box 4, Volume 6)
  - Aviation Atlas, 1933-1934 (Box 4, Volume 7)
- Pilot log books, maps, and pamphlets
  - 14 log books, 1929-1941 (Box 5)
  - 1 aeronautical maps (Box 5)
  - Aeronautical pamphlets (Box 5)
  - Copy of The New Cadet System of Ground School Training, 1935-1936 edition (Box 5)
- Herbert M. Peters family, personal papers
  - Pilot's license and mechanic's license, neg. and pos., 1927-1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - H.M. Peters Miscellany (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Misc. financial records, 1940-1942 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Check book, 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Check book, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Girl Scout Camp Comstock financial records, Dorothy B. Peters, treasurer, 1939
  - First National Bank Statements, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Inventories, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Cayuga Motor Corp. invoices, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Food invoices, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Invoices, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Menus, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Accounts, menus (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cancelled check, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- School District #16, Town of Ulysses, D.B. Peters
  - Bank statements, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Collector's receipts, 1939-1941 (Box 6, Folder 16)